Отлично. DEF CON 22, взлом лифтов. Я просто потрясен.
Люди здесь и сейчас
слушают нас. [аплодисменты] Мы вас тоже любим.
И нам очень нравится что DEF CON
позволил нам выступить,
хоть нам и сказали, что это будет
последний доклад в последний день.
Ну вы же понимаете, взламывание вещей
Итак, почему мы здесь? О чем мы расскажем?
Почему мы занимаемся этим? Кто-то из вас знает меня.
Я Дэвиант. У меня есть своя пентест-фирма. Мы вламываемся в здания. То есть мы работаем на физическом уромене
Многие здания используют лифты
как часть модели защиты.
Они не должны этого делать.
Меня зовут Говард. Я не представляю
Payne Elevators, несмотря на мою фамалию.
Я не представляю взгляды и мнение
своего работодателя. Я пью бурбон,
он пьет дешёвое пиво. При взломе лифта
многое может пойти не так.
Лифты считаются самой безопасной формой передвижения,
если исходнить из количества пройденных километров.
Они практически всегда работают в соответсвии
с ожиданиями. Большинство людей никогда
не травмировались лифтами
Они могли застревать, но никто не пострадал.
Большинство травмируемых это люди,
работающие в механизированной зоне, такой как
шахта, машинное отделение, яма.
Это касается парней, вроде меня. Вы можете сделать
с собой действительно плохие вещи, если вы полный идиот.
Эта нога была спасена.
- Да, эта нога была спасена.
Нас не беспокоит,
что вы достаточно глупы, чтобы убить себя,
скорее на беспокоит, что вы сломаете что-то,
потому что это весело.
Так что да.
Вертолет, да?
Вертолет на эскалаторе
Это все весело, пока ты не станешь виновным в уголовном преступлении с ущербом на тысячи долларов
Плюс само уголовное наказание.
Не делайте этого. В целом, после этого доклада
вы будете смотреть на лифты иначе
Вы начнёте замечать всякие мелочи в лифтах
Как говорится, "если она не хочет,
чтобы её трогали, не трогай её"
Если не знаешь, что произойдёт,
не поворачивай ключ, не нужно.
Я просто говорю смешные вещи,
но мы профессионалы. Мы хотим,
чтобы вы знали об этих вещах,
но мы не хотим, что вы пробовали их.
Если, конечно, у вас нет
действительно хорошего документа,
подготовленный юристом.
Итак, лифты в целом делятся на два типа
Некоторые из них гидравлические.
Их поршень толкает снизу
Другой тип - тяговый. При этом используются стальные
тросы. Тяговый лифт, как правило,
приводимый в движение мотором в машинном отделении,
которое находится над кабиной
Мотор тянет тросы и двигает
кабину с противовесом
Лифты обычно ездят на двух
рельсах с направляющими роликами типа
тех, что вы видите на слайде
Они не фиксированы.
Иногда вы увидите направляющие башмаки
вместо таких роликов, как здесь,
но принцип такой:
лифт просто движется вверх и
вниз по этим рельсам
Подъёмный механизм делает основную работу,
а ролики это способ аккуратно направлять
кабину. Думайте об этом,
как о скольжении вверх и вниз по
рельсам. Большинство людей в этой комнате,
взаимодействую с лифтами
через панели вроде этой.
Слева работающая панель.
Когда вы нажимаете на кнопку,
происходит регистрация вызова кабины.
Вы говорите лифту, куда конкретно
вы ходите попасть
И наоборот, когда вы в коридоре,
вы нажимаете кнопки вверх и вниз,
вы регистрируете команды направления,
но на самом деле вы не говорите лифту, куда ехать
Это называется вызов из коридора.
Кнопки указывающие направления нужны,
чтобы вы не были говнюками
Пожалуйста, не делайте этого.
Опять же, вся мощь находится
в моторном отсеке наверху
или внизу, не в самой кабине. Итак, это
тяговые двигатели без редуктора. Я думаю,
эти работают от постоянного тока.
Они обычно используются в более высоких
зданиях, чтобы достигать
скоростей, необходимых для эффективного
перемещения внутри высотки.
На другом конце спектра находятся моторы
типа этого
Он гидравлический. Система очень простая.
Там есть контроллер с правой стороны и
гидравлический насос, который
поднимает лифты. Вы никогда не увидите
гидравлический лифт в здании выше
восьми этажей. - Самый высокий, что я видел,
обслуживал 8 этажей. - Он был с тросами или без?
- Не, это был Dover HIGHdraulic
Он сказал про контроллер на
стене. Это и есть его мозг всей системы
У лифтов есть можество разных датчиков,
которые
говорят о его текущей скорости,
текущем положении, открыты или закрыты двери.
Множество параметров. Эти данные
попадают в контроллер, и на их основании
он принимает решения:
Должен ли он запустить двигатель дверей?
Должен ли он основной двигатель поднимать кабину или опускать?
Мы знаем, что говорим очень быстро.
На самом деле, мы может выступать лучше,
но мы хотим показать всё, что у нас есть,
поэтому мы болтаем без умолку. Если вы
хотите разобраться в этом подробнее,
скачайте слайды позже. Но
мы хотим показать вам ключи и
кое-что еще. Итак, номер один
наиболее примитивными формами датчиков являются
концевые выключатели или просто концевики.
Они находятся в верхней и нижней частях шахты.
Они нужны для определения,
когда лифт подъезжает к концу направляющей.
Здесь вы видите три штуки рядом и четвёртый еще выше.
Два нижних - замедлители. Когда лифт приближается
к верхнему этажу, он замыкает первый, а затем второй концевики,
лифт начинает замедляться, скорость падает,
пока не замкнётся третий, который называется
нормальный предел. Когда
лифт на нормальном пределе,
он находится ровно на верхнем этаже.
Вам, наверное, интересно,
а зачем нужен четвёртый?
Он срабатывает,
когда лифт вот-вот сойдёт с рельсов.
То есть ему буквально больше некуда ехать.
Это последний предел.
Если он срабатывает, это не так просто исправить.
Его нельзя просто выключить и включить.
Хотя мы видели, как люди пытались это сделать
в торговом центре. - Да, видели.
Это устройство называется энкодер.
Двигатель при работе вращает его индикатор,
что позволяет контроллеру знать,
сколько оборотов сделал мотор за
определенное количество времени.
Благодаря ему можно вычислить скорость,
с которой движется кабина. Она должна
сопоставляться с данными от
других датчиков, например,
указателем положения, лифт
в шахте магнитным или каким-ли другим образом
сообщает контроллеру, где он находится
Забавно как лифт иногда сходит с ума. Если лифт потерялся
в шахте, ему нужен способ узнать, где он находится,
поэтому он полностью проедет шахту сверху вниз,
чтобы исправить ошибки. Возможно вы
когда-нибудь были в лифте, который
вдруг поехал не туда, куда вы ему сказали,
а просто прошел всю шахту вверх и вниз,
и сделал вид, что всё в порядке?
Всё дело в том, что данные с датчиков
были несогласованы
с тем, что думал контролер.
Все они обрабатываются в нём и,
если что-то не согласуется,
лифт паникует, он может
остановится или сделает что-нибудь ещё.
- В машинном отделении есть тормоза,
которые держат кабину,
когда лифт спокойно стоит в шахте
Когда лифт движется,
они отпускаются. Есть и другие
виды тормозов. Экстренные.
Люди, наверное, слышали, что лифт
не может упасть. Это
в целом верно. Устройства слева
называются гувернёры
Это центробежное устройство, когда
лифт ускоряется, маховик на оси
будет вращаться быстрее и быстрее.
в конце концов кулачки
вылетят, механизм сработает, и
кабель будет зафиксирован. Это остановит
кабину. Устройство справа более современное.
Оно называется веревочный захват. Оно предотвращает
неожиданное движение вверх.
Люди обычно боятся, что лифт упадёт вниз.
На самом деле вы должны бояться, что он "упадёт" вверх.
Дело в том, что противовес тяжелее кабины.
Недавно было видео, где лифт ехал вверх не останавливаясь,
пока не врезался в потолок.
Да, кажется, это было
в Чили. Эта штука бы предотвратила это.
В целом, мы хотим сказать, что эти механизмы
очень простые.
Вы можете посмотреть и понять, как они работают.
вы можете видеть, что они действительно безопасны.
Это демонстрация оригинального рельсового захвата
Это то, что сделало Элайджа Грейвс Отиса знаменитым
Если канаты перерезать, лифт не рухнет вниз.
И это не американском шоу, это Британское телевидение,
этот человек был поднят
очень высоко, а потом они перерезали веревку.
Этот человек не упал. Кабина в порядке.
И это была демонстрация того, что
Отис показывал на Всемирных ярмарках.
Потому что до него лифты действительно
были небезопасны. Но в наши дни
они очень безопасны.
Верно. Принцип работы лифта известен уже
около 2000 лет.
Но у него не было систем, гарантирующих безопасность.
Именно это изобрёл Отис. - Касательно современных системы
типа тех, что вы видели на слайде с гувернёром.
В шахте также есть, несколько веревок, как мы их
называем. На самом деле это металлические тросы.
Есть отдельные системы
веревок, путешествующие вместе с кабиной постоянно,
если что гувернёр захватывает трос,
они тянут за рычаг тормоза на кабине, будь они
зажимными или какими-то еще.
В системе есть масса стопоров,
чья задача - не дать вам умереть. И лифты делают это
действительно хорошо. Если всё остальное
откажет, в яме есть буферные пружины.
Если кабина едет вниз, тормоза не работают,
или зажатые тормоза проскальзывают, в яме есть пружины
или масляные поршни, чья задача
поглотить удар кабины,
которая на полном ходу едет вниз.
Вы вряд ли умрёте, но серьёзно пострадаете.
Но не умрёте.
- Да, через год восстановитесь.
Так что лифты решают свою задачу
действительно хорошо, если вы
нормально ими пользуетесь.
Но если нет, тогда
лифты становятся небезопасными.
Например, когда вы едете на крыше кабины.
"Давай покатаемся! Давай покатаемся!"
Это кстати документальная съёмка
"Включи свет"
(Напряженная музыка)
"Это офигенно! Не могу поверить!"
Люди действительно это делали.
Они называли это лифтсёрфинг.
Не повторяйте!
(Кричит, звенит звонок)
Ну да, не становитесь этим парнем
К сожалению, именно так механика
лифтов была фатальна в прошлом.
Мы не шутим. Пожалуйста,
не делайте этого.
- Но если вы внутри кабине, и лифт
следуюет своей программе,
то он вполне безопасный. Хотели бы вы
узнать о том как заставить лифт
не следовать программе?
(аплодисменты) Самая распространенная вещь,
которую я использую как пентестер на заданиях
это вывод лифта из группы обслуживания
в независимую работу.
Когда вы нажимаете на кнопку в коридоре,
и у вас есть несколько лифтов,
они приходят не все.
Контроллер выбирает один и отправляет его
для вас, потому что они все в группе
обслуживания. Если вы вызвали этот
лифт вверх, контроллер знает,
что его пока нельзя использовать.
На этом фото лифт в независимом обслуживании,
мы видим переключатель этого режима с помощью ключа.
иногда они переключаются
тумблером, которые спрятаны за панелями.
В лифтах много скрытых панелей.
Если вы переключитесь на независимый
режим обслуживания, лифт
становится вашим. Он игнорирует все
вызовы из коридоров, кроме
тех команд, которые говорите ему вы.
Это включает в себя открытие дверей. Если
вы приехали на этаж в этом режиме, вы должны
кнопкой приказать лифту "открыть дверь", или
"закрой дверь". Я прятался внутри лифтов
атакуемых зданий в течение нескольких часов просто
на независимом обслуживании, потому что
она никуда не едет. Люди
могут продолжать вызвать лифты весь
день. Никто никогда не замечает:
"Эй, а почему лифт номер семь
не работает весь день?". Нет, ты
просто пользуешься первым
приехавшим. Однажды я сидел
на офисном стуле в лифте и
ждал, пока все не разойдутся
по домам. Потом я впустил Боба
и мы пробрались внутрь датацентра
[Смех] Да, независимое обслуживание
реально полезно, если
вы пентестер. Потому что лифт
полностью выходит из обслуживающей
группы и теперь принадлежит только вам.
Есть ещё один подобный режим,
он называется "Оператор лифта"
и имеет
свои корни в истории. Когда-то
в лифте действительно был лифтёр,
который перемещал кабину вверх или
вниз с помощью рукоятки, как на этом
фото. Так на автоматической системе,
вы бы увидели что-то вроде этого
за панелью с замком. Есть кнопки
вверх и вниз, чтобы лифтёр
подал сигнал, что
хочет изменить направление.
К примеру в кабине может быть много
людей или находиться VIP, поэтому
нужно перестать собирать вызовы
из коридоров в этом направлении
Эта кнопка именно это и делает,
иногда на ней есть надпись "без остановки"
или аббревиатура "NS", которая позволяет
лифту продолжать движение в том же
направлении и игнорировать все вызовы.
Когда лифт приехал куда нужно,
все те вызовы никуда не делись.
В конце концов он соберёт всех
пассажиров, которые ждут. Это
просто способ сказать, что кабина
полна или что-то в этом духе
Это как вскрытие закрытой двери,
которая никуда не ведёт. Поэтому
прекращайте это делать
- За исключением одного варианта
- Спросите нас про логические контроллеры,
и о том, как они [работают?]... Короче,
мы думаем, что этот режим порождён
независимым обслуживанием
Кто-то увидел лифт, где оператор держал
дверь закрытой, потому что вы должны это
делать в этом режиме
И началось: "Ого! вы видели,
что этот парень сделал?
Я хочу это повторить!"
Ты не сможешь, долбоёб, если только
у тебя нет ключа. Что если вам нужен
высший приоритет в обслуживании,
но вы не хотите нанимать человека, который
будет торчать в лифте круглыми сутками?
- Есть два типа приоритетных услуг.
Один из них режим экспресс-приоритета,
другой - исполнительного приоритета.
Мы уже упоминали,
что лифт принимает вызовы
в том же направлении,
в котором он уже движется.
Если пассажиры едут вверх,
по пути он собирает все
вызовы наверх.
Когда он доедет до верхнего этажа,
направление меняется. В этом случае
у пользователя может быть ключ или карта,
чтобы сказать лифту, что он более важен,
чем обычные люди. Разница между режимами в том, что
здесь лифт может изменить направление движения,
чтобы как можно быстрее добраться до этого человека.
- Что же происходит, когда должен проехать VIP?
Это на самом деле забавно, особенно в лифтах
с голосовым интерфейсом в духе "Едем вниз"/"Едем вверх"
Управляющий вставляет свой ключ,
резервируя лифт. При этом вы слышите
сообщение: "Этот лифт используется
для другой цели, пожалуйста, немедленно
покиньте его, когда откроются двери".
- Он вас просто вышвыривает. Отлично
Возможно, вы встречали людей из некоторых
сообществ со своими убеждениями и правилами
Возможно, благодаря им вы знаете о режиме Шаббата.
Кто-нибудь видел лифт с режимом Шаббата?
Или вы видели религиозный фильм с Билл Марч?
Он нужен для людей, которым нельзя взаимодействовать
с механическими системами в шаббат, такими как кнопки
и тумблеры.
Режим шаббата позволяет людям покинуть
здание. Он едет на верхний этаж,
а потом спускается,
останавливаясь на каждом этаже
Это что-то типо хакинга Бога.
А! Вот, я нашел лазейка в Писании. Так что
я умнее тебя. Это режим Шаббата. И у многих
лифтов он есть.
Особенно в больших городах типо Нью-Йорка.
У этого режима есть еще фишки
Спросите нас позже о том, почему он
делает не совсем то, что может
показаться на первый взгляд.
А религиозным организациям стоит
перепроверить свои документы. "[Обход] при перегрузке".
Эта штука должна включаться чаще, но не включается
Лифты знают, насколько они загружены
Если вы загрузили в него слишком
много хлама, он пищит и злится.
У него есть датчики веса
Он может использовать эти данные,
чтобы сказать:
"Хм, я набрал уже много народу, я почти полный
Лучше я не буду останавливаться
на каждом оставшемся вызове,
иначе будет:
"Извините, нет места". "Извините".
И так пять этажей подряд.
Ага. [Надеюсь, если вам понравится
надежда в Нью-Йорке] Почему это включают
не так часто за гранью моего понимания.
Почему [антихулиган (anti-nuisance)] не включён
из коробки?. Если ты долбаный...
Дерпи Хувз и любишь нажимать все кнопки
Вы знали, что лифты умеют сбрасывать всё это?
- Продолжай. Подожди, подожди.
Бум, готово! (Смеется)
Это удивительно.
Давай еще. Едем вниз... 1,2,3 и бум.
Отключился. Как будто они знают, что мы здесь
Это называется "[антихулиган (anti-nuisance)]"
Есть режим работы в часы пик,
когда работники приходят в офис утром
Включается в определенные часы.
Есть множество оптимизаций,
которые вам может включить квалифицированный
специалист по лифтам. Есть режимы, когда
вы не хотите впускать или выпускать людей
из здания в определённых обстоятельствах
- Я видел в музее режим под названием "режим бунта".
Я подумал, что это за хрень?
Владельцы здания хотели таким образом,
запрещать лифту обслуживание первого этажа.
При этом лифт можно использовать
на всех других этажах. То есть, кто-то
из охранников нажимает кнопку
и говорит: "О Боже, снаружи бунт".
И когда он её нажимает...
- "Оккупируй Тальсу!" [протесты в США в 2011]
Лифт просто перестаёт реагировать на
первый этаж, потому что если
кто-то заберётся в здание
с улицы, он может добраться
на лифте куда угодно и делать плохие вещи.
- Но главная фишка режим бунта в том,
что лифт продолжает работать на остальных этажах.
Вы можете смотреть из окна своих апартаментов
и сетовать: "Ох! Ну почему 99% людей не довольны
объедками, что мы им даем?" Вы продолжаете ездить между
этажами. Вам наплевать, вы просто не можете выйти в холл.
- Помимо социальных потрясений
Есть также сейсмические. Возможно, вы живёте
в сейсмически стабильном регионе и никогда
не видели этого. А может вы живёте
Южной Калифорнии, где в лифтах есть
маленькая лампочка с надписью
"сейсимичность(seismic)".
Люди любят шутить: "Чувак, если её нажать,
начнётся землетрясение". Нет,
это просто лампочка, которая загорается
при землетрясении. При этом вы должны выйти
из кабины, как можно быстрее.
Механизм обычно устроен он очень просто:
это кольцо на "струне", как её называют,
через которое пропущен металлический
кабель вдоль всей шахты
Если кабина начнет раскачиваться
в стороны, это кольцо касается струны,
замыкая цепь, что говорит контроллеру
о неожиданном боковом движении
Это единственный вид аварийного режима,
который может поднять вас наверх
Это может быть неинтуитивно, но, если
вы задумаетесь, один из рисков во время
землетрясения в том, что если кабина или
противовесом сойдут с рельс, по которым
они ездят, в итоге вы получите
противовес весом тонну или полторы,
качающийся рядом с вами.
Поэтому вас нужно увезти от него
подальше, пускай и вверх.
>> How many people maybe work in a
hospital or medical facility,
you may have seen code [blue
service. Right on. That's
medical priority. Imagine the
highest VIP priority where a
doctor or an emergency
personnel will use a key
and they will seize an elevator
the closest one responds and it
becomes their elevator until the
key comes back down. Hospital
also has code pink. It's baby
theft mode. If the baby gets moved
unauthorized, the elevators can
basically turn into security
recall devices which is its own
mode that you can program
independent of a hospital. It
turns the elevator into a man
trap. It'll deliver the person
to a floor of your designation
And keep the doors
shut. Or it'll psych it will
doors manually so they can't
hide. There's all kinds of
fascinating things you can do
with elevator security and
there's other things people try
to do and we're going to shit
all over that in a minute.
There's also just modes you see,
if you start looking into this,
you'll see security service.
This is kind of a catch all key
switch. It doesn't always mean
what you think. Like all the key
switches in this photo are
actually the same keyway.
Look at one of them that the
security service looks beat to
hell. So I asked the desk at
this hotel, hay, I work with
elevators, I'm curious, are you
having security incidents every
frickin' day? And he's like no.
The maid use that to go to the
basement. Just 'cause use see
something, it doesn't actually
do what you think it does. One
of the most misunderstood modes
is firefighters emergency
operation. You're seeing here
two key switches that are
instrumental in the use of an
elevator during a fire. When the
heat or smoke condition is
detected by the buildings's fire
alarm system there are contact
that is  ‑ ‑   ‑ ‑ controller
which indicates that there is
such a condition and that it's
no longer safe to run the
elevators. You've probably seen
signs. They're supposed to be at
every landing. That say  ‑ ‑
>> You shouldn't be able to. The
elevator should go away from you
and sit] in the lobby. It
should. >> But the smokes and
heats  are near the landing so the
building can be in fire down there, and
the elevator over there is still
working SDWL but if the elevator
has platformed in the lobby, the
firefighter can take control of
it. And they can drive it in the
building and in a very powerful
way. >> Just to be clear, phase
one is when the smoke and heat
detecters go off. It brings the
elevators down to the lobby or
some other designated floor  ‑ ‑
‑ ‑ once the car is on phase
one, then they can go in and use
their key to activate phase two
which allows them to run the
car. Over riding the fact that
this other is logged out.
>> Over riding is pretty much
everything. You think
independent mode is powerful?
Firefighter phase is way more
powerful. Fuck you, I'm a
firefighter. >> By code it has
to be disabling any security
systems. So that firefighters
can get to the floor they need
to go to. So there's one more
mode that's even more powerful
than this. In the elevator
world, who can ever be more
important than a firefighter?
>> Us. (Laughing) . >> Yeah,
elevator guys right? . So
hoistway inspection, if
you can take command of the
elevator and get into the hoist
way, which is superfuck]ing
dangerous. If you don't know
what you're doing, don't god dam
do this. If you do, there are
all kinds of controls in there,
you should not have anything to
do with because you don't know
what they are. >> Exactly. >> Oh
my God, you'll see something
about that later maybe. So
plenty of buildings, try to use
elevators adds part of their
security model. Maybe you seen a
building where you can't
register a haul call. Or you
have to use a key. Maybe there's
no haul buttons, there's only a
key switch. Maybe you've been in
situations where a badge reader
is used or hotel key card is
used. So not being able to make
the elevator come to you and you
can drive it layer, we'll show
you an interesting trick about
that. Maybe there have been
situations where you can get in
the elevator and certain floors
are locked out. What kind of locks
are these? Anybody who's been in
the lock (inaudible).
(Indiscernible) locks are shit
ones. Those are valid answers.
all the elevator key switches,
almost all of them are way for
lock. Some of them are harder I
think. But you can pick them
later if you want. This is not a
way for lock. That is a medical
lock. I'm very interested on
floor seven. But anything like
lock outs or badge systems,
these are common ways that
people try to treat the elevator
as restricting your movement.
They try to say, oh you know,
someone couldn't get to floor
seven or 20, or whatever unless
they have the right credential.
Duck FAUK bunch of that. That's
not how you should think of your
elevator. You want to secure a
elevator? This is what your
doing. What's going on here.
>> Sure. We had a job WOUN time
in a facility and we came across
this. I said gee, THS a
interesting way to secure a
hallway. (Indiscernible) this
key. Let's just show them. >> It
was a jail. It's a giant cage in
front of the elevator. Unless
you're doing this, think of your
elevators as a stairwell. Think
of them as a stair way where
lazy people don't use their
legs. Everything we just showed
you we'll just shit all over it.
Remember there was no haul call
buttons, you can't get the
elevator to show up, I use my
magic hack haxor
paper. Well what happened there?
Well the elevator happened to be
at the floor, so somebody
tripped the safety inch. And
it's a really smart idea to
stick things through the hoist
way doors. >> No it's not.
>> And also to be clear, that's
not a universal trick. In fact
that's unusual it did work.
Those sensors should have been
disabled when the doors were
closed. But this kid somewhere
on YouTube happened to find out
that it worked. >> Most of what
we do most of what we're going
to talk to you about over riding
systems just by using the key
SWECHs. There's key switches
inside all  ‑ ‑ how many people
have seen panels in elevators
that pop open. Some of those
panels are locked. None of you
would have ever picked this.
Interesting point, there's
something call add slam panel.
It's like a spring loaded latch.
You can just. (Making noise.)
And it'll pop open. But inside
the panels, you'll see like look
independent service that we told
you about. Hoist way service,
you shouldn't touch it. Card
reader disabled. Let me turn I
don't have my key, let me turn
off my that function. The
industry is oh washed in
different key SWIFs and
different keys that you'll start
to see in the industry they call
it graffiti. In the motor rooms
and car panels, you'll see notes
from elevator guys and gals.
You'll start to think that keys
are really different all over
the place. And yes, there's a
lot of keys. If you're on a pen
test job, you might try to look
for the elevator keys. Sometimes
you just find them. But if
you're on a legislate elevator
job, what this man has done for
years now is catalog every key
he's ever seen on every job ever
ever. As far as I know, Howard's
the only one that has a
collection of every elevator key
he's found SXN he knows what it
does. This is not Howard's key
collection by the way. This is
Howard's key collection. >> [Applause] >>
might notice this is actually an
old photo. Every elevator  ‑ ‑
there's all different brands and
fixtures. And you can just spot
them. >> So when you have the
experience to look at something
and say ah, I've seen that on
another job or I've seen the
catalog or company's flyers and
visited the trade shows. It's
all the same. They use the same
things everywhere. And that is
one of the main points to take
away from this. If they sold you
a key switch, the buttons look
alike and the key switches look
alike. The buttons looks alike,
hay my elevator uses Adams,
guess what, your key probably
operates that other Adams
elevator. >> There's modernizing
that happens. We're in the
Rio right? Dover impulsion. How
many people seen those buttons a
million times. >> When I started
to try to learn this, I'm on
jobs, I'm like holy shit, I'm
pretty sure I have ooh key for
this. What is it? I'm like I
don't know what it is. How thick
is the halo. What font is  ‑ ‑
they all look the same to you
until you start learning it. And
you can type the fixtures just
by glancing at them and you know
what keys (indiscernible).
>> That's totally hell vet KA.
>> Yeah, epiKA. >> And the other
is innovation. >> It says it on
the slide. >> Like an article
narrow I think. >> I could do
this to him all day. Now if you
want your own elevator keys,
like people sell them online.
Many people probably shouldn't
be and you probably shouldn't
buy them because they're ripping
you off. Like this key set is
almost $9 a key. >> And its
actually has to ship USB ground
because the smoke isn't the
picture is included. So it's  ‑
‑ I don't know what half these
things are to tell you the
truth. They took an KOOEL guy
that retired 20  years ago and
copied every single one, because
the fixtures these are used for
are completely dead and long
gone. >> These are the most
popular ones you can find
online  ‑ ‑ you can get 17 of
them in the set. >> Don't get me
wrong though. The vendor did two
nice things, they took clear
straight on photos of the keys.
With the labels visible. And
they really took care to make
sure this was going to be
comprehensive. This was really
perfect for your fire department
as long as your fire department
simultaneously the state of
Massachusetts  ‑ ‑   ‑ ‑ South
Carolina and Arizona. So if.
>> So if that's what your tricks
are rolling through, that's your
job. Rock out. >> What probably
happened of course is the vendor
had a contact. And someone kept
handing them keys and say I've
seen this work or this is a
buyer key and they've had, well
we better put it on our set.
>> So when you buy keys online,
from shitty sources, you don't
know what you're getting
exactly. You might be getting a
key that's speed run on a
duplicator that kind of has the
right bittings vs. a coat cut
and original factory key  ‑ ‑
and going on elevator keys.com.
Is anyone going to sell them in
this room. How many people are
going to try to call elevator
keys now? >> Don't bother, read
the verification requirements
they will not sell to you unless
you are legitimate personnel >> The
guy AS I can D. I tried on the
phone a lot. (Laughing) . But in
general, this a industry way
behind the times on security. So
WHOOND of key switch is this on
the floor too? What kind is it?
you've been to the village.
>> Tubular. >> What'd the guy
tell you. >> This is a true
story and I swear, it was a
casino, and the building's
architect was present at a
meeting, he happened to mention
he had a personal investment
in selecting the switches on the elevator.
And he made a comment to the
effect of no one would ever be
able to pick that. >> That's a
tubular lock. >> Right. >>
(Laughing) so yeah, it's an
industry where like someone says
so MEDCO is a great brand. We'll
get tons and tons of MEDCO key
switches. I asked Howard and
said let me see those keys. And
then I grabbed bob ex. And I
lined them all up. It's a
mastered system where half the
bittings aren't even mastered
and the rest is just a huge
sample size I was able to
determine the master fitting. I
had Howard once send me a
picture. And it's a Dover
system. Yeah, a Dover DEE R key,
but look where I found it.
There's all kind of reuse in the
industry because you think your
keys are unique, and it's just a
supplier calling a supplier
calling a warehouse and shipping
them thousands of the same
cylinder. Stock locks.
Whatever's cheeper. You also
have industries where they try
to start enable shit online. So
MCE, it's like, oh, our, we have
this box that you're going to
see later. Yeah, it's hooked up
and you put it on your network
make sure you can fix it. Add
an account called MCE support
make user account MCE support
‑ just make it all for the same
password everywhere. Because we
need to get in. This is the MCE
system that they need to get
into remotely. This is supposed
to be forward facing from your
net work. This is up here  ‑ ‑
‑ ‑ attached to the controller
so you can do all kinds of
remote management. Is this the
kind of thing you think is smart
to be publicly facing with a
user and password on the router
of your building called MCE
support where you can access
these features remotely? Raise
your hand if that's a good idea.
>> In this room a lot of hands
are going up because we want
that to be a good idea. >> But
it's cool, they paid for
extended support for X[P].
(Laughing) . >> There's also
things like Otis elite service.
>> As your building requirements
change, you can customize your
elevator's operation, with a
simple telephone call to our
elite engineers. >> It won't be
a problem. I'm going to take
elevator number two from the
bank. >> JOU don't have the
independent key switch, just
call the company up. I'm totally
bob Jones. This is my building.
On star for elevators. Bluff
your way, and I'm sure you get
the elevator to do things. It's
all remote management. You have
like this in the industry. This
fire keys we showed you. They
tried to push for a uniform fire
key. >> Does anybody know what
[F]DOK is in. [F]DOK one was the
key that was adopteded in the
2007 of the ASME A17.1 Safety
Code for Elevators & Escalators
‑ ‑ they
wanted to eliminate firefighters
having to fire around keys that
were over priced and weighed
pounds, they said let's just
make one standard key. Only you
can have it. >> Yup, only
elevator and emergency personnel
can use this. >> So let's just
publish the bitting. >> yeah
let's put that in the code right
there. Smart. >> [Applause] >>
This is the
kind of thing you see in the
industry. It's a industry that
hasn't had any security
background pushing on any of
these topics. Not to mention
it's all circuits at the end of the
day. It's all naked on the inside.
If you pop open the panel
or if the panels just aren't secured
why are you messing with key
switches? You could just bridge
the contacts (multiple voices)
swing panel opens up. It's
insane. It's not secure at all.
>> This is not secured either.
What's happening? I'm not a
(indiscernible) speaker. This is
his first time on a stage at DEF
CON. >> It's very, very quiet,
they're hunting newbs. How many
glasses are you (inaudible) oh
why thank you. >> Who was here
at the handcuff talk where goons
raided the stage with ninja
swords and piracy. And I think
we handcuffed DeCode to a railing
and Ray had to get him out of the
cuffs. This is why  ‑ ‑ people
have to bitch that DEF CON's
changing. It's BlackHat now.
And BlackHat's RSA. This doesn't
happen at BlackHat >> To our
new speakers! >> [Applause] >>
Thank you fellas. >> This is the final
the editions of shot the newb for
this year. So I'd like to thank
my shot new colleagues. You guys
like this? Should we do it again
next year? (Applause.) >> Right
on. >> (Inaudible) your timing.
>> There's no talk after us.
We'll just keep talking and
answering questions all night if
we want. If you want to see fun
crazy, award ceremonies are
happening right now where other
people are speaking for us. So
yeah, we'll hang out until hotel
throws us out of here if you
have crazy elevator questions.
Badge systems AUSHLGS kind of
the key cards right. People use
those in a lot of buildings.
There's a lot of attacks about
key cards. That could be its own
entire talk. Cloning
credentials, fortunately it's
already been another talk. Mad
STREK research and years ago  ‑
‑   ‑ ‑ and educational where
that look at mad STREK madness.
Look at a lot of his approximate
card stuff. If you want to be
kind of that cloning. Or be like
us, turn off the card reader and
use independent mode. In
general, that's what pen testers
do. If you're going to break
into a building and leverage the
elevators what are you doing?
We're optimizing his giant key
ring and just using it for pen
testing. His key ring's cool,
but I sat around with Howard and
I actually just took all of his
key  ‑ ‑ here's your giant
database and and here's your
list. I was like okay, screw
lights and fans. I'm not going
to turn off the lights or make
out with someone. But I'm like,
okay, give me independent
service and floor cut outs and
then we spread all these keys
out. Group these into how common
they are. So we have collections
of keys that are like this is
70  percent of America. This is
the other like 20  percent. This
you'll basically never see.
This, I wouldn't even buy. But
I'm crazy so I did. So yeah, we
grouped these up and if you are
in the industry, maybe you speak
to us later if you want some
independent service keys and
shit like that. Maybe you want
some fire keys. You can fuck
right off. Legal told us we
could not give you those unless
we have J a special training
which maybe we'll write some
day. I promise we're going to do
that at some point. But here,
you want an example, we have to
show  ‑ ‑ this is my favorite
client story ever regarding use
of key switches. There
was a building, and this building
everyone went in through the
front and at the front there was
a guard desk, they had to show
credentials and they had to badge
in blah blah blah. There was
an elevator system and it
serviced the back entrance. They
said okay, this door, you'd need
a badge or something to get in.
But no one really  ‑ ‑ everyone
just used it to park their car
out back. And this elevator,
even if you were in that lobby
that, rear lobby, the elevator
wouldn't go anywhere because you
kneed a badge. If you didn't
have a badge, they said there's
no reason to have a guard back
here. No one could take this
elevator somewhere else. If you
seize control of this elevator and
drive it somewhere they didn't
expect and pop out on another floor
‑ ‑ the culture of this office
environment such no one
questioned us once we were in.
And when when he showed what
you're about to see to the
building own, you'll love their
reaction. It blew their mind. So
here we are in the parking deck
he's carrying a camera and
got the security footage. The
door's locked. Not very well.
But now this elevator, we could
call it, but we couldn't do
anything with it unless we had
our keys. >> On on. >> Phase
one, phase two. >> Yeah, now, we
did that a little fast. The
elevator controller got a little
mad at the order in which we did
that. >> Got very mad. We broke
the elevator. >> Yeah, we had to
fuss with it for a while before
we got it working again. But you
know, we got upstairs, so
there's that. And then there you
are. You're upstairs you're
outside. And we showed this
footage. The client was like
holy crap, how'd you get in we
trained in engineering. And we
were like I socialed your
elevator bro. And the response
literally, that can't happen. We
were told that elevator can't go
up.  >> (Laughing) >> we're like what'd
you just say? It's an elevator.
It has one job. Elevators go up.
(Laughing). But yeah yeah, you
have keys, if you can take over
the key switches, this is why it
was such a big to do in New York
when this gentleman on Ebay  ‑ ‑
most of these keys are old and
dusted any way, but this guy was
selling keys and the New York
Post wanted to make a sky is
falling out of it. And a geting
a camera shoved in his face.
Like oh my God you're selling
keys to the terrorists and then
they print a you a fucking
article sh\owing the keys. And we
were like no we were told you
can't copy those keys.
>> (Inaudible) all of those.
Exactly. So but the, in general,
yeah, these are like shitty
bullshit bad versions of the
photos. Here's a nice photo of
that key. And you'll learn why
it was not a security breech
that this is the New York City
key. This is like thee can that
got all the curfuffle. It's called
the 2642 key. It's a Yale. It's an
unrestricted blank. Do you know why
it's called that? the bitting code
is 2642. >> [Laughter] >>
And it's not really,
because the first position isn't
used. So yeah, like you saw this
and filed it in an office blank
and we were able to do that in
New York and things. Now that's
just one city. It's not like
an entire three state region
would use another key. That's
also an unrestricted blank. And
that also has a really easy code
to decode. We're just going to
drop a lot of FRIKing keys on
you right now. We're going to
get through these slides fast.
>> I'm going to take this slide
because there's an amazing story
behind this. I was buying keys
to make my key ring as complete
as possible. And I came across
something very unusual. I was
purchasing some time for locks
with a key. I found that was
easier to do. Sometimes people
would ask questions a little bit
less. Ordering one key in
general  ‑ ‑ so I was sometimes
just buying the lock with the
key. So in one case, I bought a
lock box. Like we're seeing right
here. One of these little red
lock boxes. And the key  ‑ ‑ the
cylinder on the front is
operated by this exact key that
you're seeing here. And I
ordered another one, it was
state of Tennessee key. It was
keyed to the state of Tennessee.
Except it didn't come with
the key. I looked at ate and
said it's just a flat key. And
it's open. Right? So how old is
this key? >> Probably like a
hundred‑ year‑ old. >> This is
made by a company called game
well that made those fire
boxes that you pull on the
street before everybody had
telephones and the firefighters
would come and reset the boxes.
Somebody somewhere said let's
reuse the key. Here's the story.
I called up the company and who
sold me the key box. I said wait
a minute you sold my one with T
the key and  ‑ ‑ that's because
you asked for the Tennessee box.
They couldn't sell him  ‑ ‑ if
you called and said I need the
Tennessee key, sorry you're not
authorized. I'm sorry, I had
something crazy in my ear, I
need the game well Christmas
tree key. No problem. How about
if you live in Indiana show of
hands. Anybody? You have good
gun laws. You don't have good
fire service keys though  ‑ ‑
tubular keys. We couldn't buy
the key, we could pick the lock
box that's siting up here after
we picked it. We measured the
bidding. Used a little HURDdy
GURdy chop chop. We made a key.
It's open. There's your frickin'
Indiana key. Some states aren't
using systems that are quite so
unrestricted. Kentucky. How many
people go to Derbycon. I should
see more hands. Derbycon
is great event >> [Applause] >>
Kentucky. Their keyboxes use
use a MEDCO key. It's a classic,
but it's a MEDCO cam lock. You
can buy that you can't buy the
key, just the cam lock. What can
you do to buy the box because it
ships open. If you take the tail
piece off oh a MEDCO cam lock.
The front slides out. What
happens then? You peel off the
top plait and have an [extra one
with you if you're doing it
nefariously. There's bob here
he's helping to get this thing
apart. Holy crap. It's that
easy. There's the pins, there's
the springs, let's put them on a
MEDCO tray. Let's do some
measurements. Let's compare that
from what we know from our code
books. Let's put it back
together under five minutes you
put a new brass plait on the
top. You're supposed to stamp
that down with a stamp tool. The
lock Smith we got that from  ‑ ‑
‑ ‑ we had to stamp it down
with this. We just pounded on it
with a (indiscernible) for a
while. But it's fine. And in the
end, there's your Cricken
Kentucky key. >> [Applause] >> But
wait there's more. Florida divides
their states into zones. You
can't buy the key, but you can
buy the lock. Little bit more
interesting, little bit harder
to take apart. Not that hard. If
you have a pinning tray, it's
not a cam lock tray  ‑ ‑   ‑ ‑
left right center. You can
completely check your code
books. Oh what's this? The zone
four key. What's this? It's the
zone kick six key. So zone
seven. You want all of Florida
K, seven keys instead of one.
And also we boughting the key
from Louisiana and decoded it.
And we  ‑ ‑ ... and you can also
by  ‑ ‑ we could do this all
fucking day and we have all the
god dam state keys in all the
states right now. (Applause.) So
we're not saying these are bad
locks right? We're not
(indiscernible) up here. We're
not saying MEDCO is the worst
cylinder ever and you should use
like get a (indiscernible) [F]
3D because you could try to take
it apart it'll explode in your
face and you could never put it
together again. No we're saying
you shouldn't think of your
mechanical key systems as a
single point of
resistance. They're not going to
provide you ironclad security.
They can take it apart and
measure the pins. Sure they
fucking can. >> Also there's
implementation. If you're floor
with the Knox box type of system
it's implemented a little bit
better. You can't buy the lock and
take it apart. The fire
department is authorizing to
purchase and possess a cylinder
itself. But that doesn't mean
the fire righters don't just
lose these things in the
hundred  ‑ ‑ like really? Come
on. That was over like two or
three years too. >> And I'm
talking like one a day. >> Now
this is all, again, this is fire
service operation. This is one
of the most powerful modes. It's
actually not as hard as you
think to get the keys. No we
won't just give them to you.
Maybe you'll like hack through
my laptop and get the biddings I
redacted on the slides. But  ‑ ‑
‑ ‑ there's what can you do in
the hoist way, the answer is
everything. What if you have a
building that you  ‑ ‑ you know
the fire key in the lobby that
we used  ‑ ‑ if you're not in
the lobby, what if you want to
move around the building. Well
if you seized control of the
elevator and you get on the car
top, and I don't mean you
because you shouldn't. You could
do this. On the lower right you
see where we are. The upper
right is where we want to be.
This is an elevator that is
driving itself down the hoist
way because we sent some calls
down that way. If [we want to,
we can seize the car in a way
that's completely out of
standard. You're not supposed
to do it. I've learned from
Howard, there's three ways to do
things. There's the right way,
the wrong way and the elevator
person way. >> Which is like the
wrong way faster basically.
>> So here we are  ‑ ‑ there's
the car top, all right, we're on
a mode  ‑ ‑ we're not really going
to talk about any of this
right now. But if we take
control of this elevator and we
get on to the car top, my mom
hated this video. She almost
smacked me when she saw it. What
are you doing. You shouldn't be
there. You're an idiot. So once
you're in the hoist way, you can
drive this car anywhere. It
literally doesn't matter if this
is a fed facility, this one wasn't, but
in the hoist way, your risk of
life is so great that you have
utter absolute control. You can
drive any direction. You can go
to any other floor. What kind of
security do you think the hoist
way doors have on
the other side? (Inaudible) 0.
There we are, thank you good
night. You can just send it
down. So how do we do that?
>> You've seen that little hole
right SNG. >> Real quick
disclaimer, there's another
video, where we are completely
out of control and almost
crashed in the over head. Down
down down in the black and
jumping down in the grease in
the elevator car top. Sometimes
thing can be unpredictable.
Sometimes out of your control.
So if you see that hole in the
door, that's call add
(indiscernible) hole. That is
the hole through which elevator
personnel that will  ‑ ‑ that
will usually flip a flag that
release it is door interlock. It
does two things. It keeps the
doors mechanically closed and it
also electrically signals to the
controller that the doors are
closed. So when an elevator
mechanic sticks it key in and
turn it. It unlock it is door
and sends a signal to the
controller that the door is
open, stop the cab. With that
being said, there's a million
different kinds of key, but
there's a key for every door at
the end of the the day  ‑ ‑   ‑
‑ sometimes it doesn't have a
hole, there are often ways of
interacting with the interlock
that you might not expect. >> I
know how uber this talk is, I
really do. Unfortunately, you're
trying to set up for final
ceremonies, and this track has
to end. Now I have a problem
with usually we shot this
SPAEKers, that's nice for them.
But we have little tricks up our
sleeves to lure the speakers off
stage. So I brought with me some
bait. Come on, come on speakers.
>> I'm literally not going. Because
it is not the top of the hour.
We have seven minutes and we're
going to use all seven minutes.
(Applause.) (Indiscernible)
really fast. You know people
used to stash drugs in hoist
ways because they could pop
hole. They made a lock for it.
The lock was interesting, it
would plug up the hole. The lock
had a problem in the way it was
assembled. The lock screwed
together. So if the lock screws
together and you can just
unscrew the collar, you don't
need the real key, what you can
do is say that's the speedy key.
That it's fast key. If you don't
have that key, well what if you
had any other possible key ever?
Yeah. Put a little torque on
that. Push a little harder. Oh
my, what happened there? Yeah
just unscrew the (indiscernible)
lock. Pull it apart, whatever.
Fine. Come talk to us  ‑ ‑
there's so  ‑ ‑ we're going to
skip a few slides. We're going
to show you some others. In the
end, there are some really
common guidelines we can give
you right? >> First thing if
you have an emergency phone in
the elevator that's answered by
your your security desk. This is
a case where a guy got stuck in
an elevator for over 48 hours
because the phone didn't work.
There ended up being a lawsuit.
Test your alarm bell. Make sure
it works too. >> (Speaking
simultaneously) the hoist way
should never be accessible. No
one should be in there and ride
the fucking counterweight. >> If
anybody recognizes this photo,
I'll buy you a drink at the bar.
Your motor room, should be self‑
closing self‑ locking. This is
not self‑ closing or self‑
locking and B is being operated
by a frickin' mall security
guard who shouldn't be in there
because it's dangerous. Only
elevator people should be in
there. Because you know these
guys are elevator guys. >> [Applause] >>
Know who your elevator staff is.
They are not your maintenance
crew. They are very nice sir.
Know who your people are that
provide your maintenance vs.
consulting. Know who your people
are and what they're doing. If
you have bullshit jobs and
paperwork that's not being
filled out if you have
collusion or inspection
that is don't make any sense,
what is this? There are test
tabs. It's a permanently affixed
tab that after, every year,
every five years there is
performed they fill it out
indicating the elevator passed
hopefully and it's left there so
if somebody ever has to come in
and take a look and say when the
test was done and  ‑ ‑ let us
know that OETS performed the
test, because that makes sense.
Unless the guy's name was Otis.
Elevator tests are important.
Here's a final readiness
test. (machine noise.) Yeah
and the client didn't, no it's
fine right? To be fair, the
elevator mechanic said there's
no way this is going to work.
And he made his supervisor come
down he was the one recording
it. You want to run the test,
you run the test, I'll record
it. So yeah, follow all of your
building procedures. How many
times we've coasted in on oh I'm
the elevator guy I BLONG here. I
have a shirt I bought which you
can't anymore. You can no longer
buy the uniforms forms we're
wearing right now. Pretty much
thanks (inaudible). >> I believe
they did. >> So what do you do
now? If your elevators are maybe
part of your security models and
you're like oh my God, what if
people are going to attack the
elevators because they're not
actually doing what they think,
there is a difference between
your parts oil and grease tech
at a security consultant. There
are people that do this. Not
like a lot of them. He's kind of
the only ones we've ever Maine
but your elevator controller can
actually do monitoring without
installing a fucking windows box
in the motor room. Your elevator
controller can open or close
contacts if it gets flipped on
independent mode or inspection
mode or fire mode. You could be
logging this with your access
control system or alarm system.
There are add on boards, extra
modules that you can use to make
your system better. We're going
to wrap it up in one minute with
some final tips they're useful
if you're a jackass and get
stuck. First tip, don't panic.
You're not going to run out of
air. There's a fan. And just in
general, there's oxygen. So just
relax. The second thing is, if
you're on a red team, you don't
want to use the emergency phone.
But if the main light in the cab
are off, the power's out.
There's nothing you can do. If
the cab lights are still on, you
might have a few options. .
Let's just run through a few
scripts. They're going to tell
you to hit door open. Would you
believe that happens all the
time. Someone's just siting
there. The cab is parked and
they just don't think to hit
door open. They might tell you
to hit door close and then hit
door open. This sometimes when
the door operator hadn't fully
closed the doors allows it to
fully close and signalling to
the elevator that it's safe
run. Another option would be
make sure you can register a
call to another floor. If you're
sitting there and staring at it
and it's stuck, you're stuck.
But maybe you're stuck at a
floor you don't have access to.
Badge in, etc. >> If you have a
badge, make sure it's in before
you're placing the callsment Ma.
Maybe your a authorized user and
your key switches. >> Or e‑
mailed me and bought some keys.
>> You could try the key switches
I've been stuck in elevators
where it didn't matter. And of
course, the last thing is, keep
in mind the number one cause of
encrapments is that the doors
have opened somewhere. It might
not be where you are, but it
might be. So I very hesitantly
say this you can kind of
troubleshoot the doors in a safe
way. Don't stick your hand in
the gap between the doors. Just
very gently put your palm on the
door, see if it's jiggling and
try to close them with the flat
part of your hand somewhere
square on the door. And if all
else fails, call for help.
>> I'll help you. >> Never ever
ever try to leave through the
top hatch. It doesn't lead you
anywhere and it'll fuck other
shit up. Never ever exit a
missed level car. If
you have to jump it's too far,
stay in the elevator. It's the
safest place to be, the elevator
wants to keep you alive. We
wanted to keep you alive. We
hope you learned something
today. Thank you for letting us
talk at DEF CON. (Applause.)